<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Process Improvement for Glucosamine Archives - The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/</link>
	<description>The Glucosamine Experts™</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:18:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-Favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Process Improvement for Glucosamine Archives - The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<link>/category/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We at TSI Group, the exclusive manufacturers of GlucosaGreen® vegetal glucosamine are curious about something. We know glucosamine has been around for generations. It is a common supplement taken to relieve joint pain in humans. It can also help companion animals remain active and healthy. But that’s not the curious part. What is GlucosaGreen®? GlucosaGreen® [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/">How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We at TSI Group, the exclusive manufacturers of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> vegetal glucosamine are curious about something. We know glucosamine has been around for generations. It is a common supplement taken to relieve joint pain in humans. It can also help companion animals remain active and healthy. But that’s not the curious part.</p>
<h4><strong>What is GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup>?</strong></h4>
<p>GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the same ingredient with the same bio-activity as traditional glucosamine. It is just made in a different way. Instead of harvesting the building blocks for the supplement from shellfish, we produce it by processing glucose from non-GMO corn. Same glucosamine, different process to make it. Again, nothing curious about that.</p>
<p>GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is glucosamine; the magic is in how making it impacts the environment. The process to make GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> reduces waste generation by 98% and reduces the carbon footprint by 80% over shellfish derived glucosamine. But once more, this is not what we are curious about.</p>
<h4><strong>So why are you curious?</strong></h4>
<p>We are curious because we can’t understand why anyone looking to relieve joint pain with glucosamine would ever reach for a product that is made from shellfish. We thought that maybe consumers just don’t know that it is the same supplement. So we checked a number of Google search terms to see what comes up and the one we were most intrigued by was:</p>
<p>“How to get glucosamine naturally”</p>
<p>This is a frequently asked question on Google, and there&#8217;s a good chance this is because people don&#8217;t want to take the supplement knowing that it comes from shellfish. Curiously, almost every link we found from this search contained virtually the same statement: <em>glucosamine occurs naturally in shellfish, otherwise it is made synthetically</em>. Unfortunately this is simply not true. GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is derived naturally from non-GMO corn via fermentation. That’s it. No shellfish, no extreme waste, no synthesis. But the same glucosamine as always.</p>
<p>So look for the logo and insist on GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> for you and your pet and take care of your health, your pet’s health, and the health of the planet. GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the Next Generation Glucosamine<sup>TM</sup>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/">How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 22:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Matt and Pete talk about how TSI Group came to be the experts in glucosamine and the value that will deliver for our customers. TSI Bio-Active Ingredients leads the way (naturalproductsinsider.com)</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/">Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Matt an<a href="https://www.naturalproductsinsider.com/sports-nutrition/supplyside-stories-episode-28-sustainability-commitments-tsi-group-bio-active"><img class="wp-image-997 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories-300x276.png" alt="" width="187" height="171" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories-300x276.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories.png 624w" sizes="(max-width: 187px) 100vw, 187px" /></a>d Pete talk about how TSI Group came to be the experts in glucosamine and the value that will deliver for our customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.naturalproductsinsider.com/sports-nutrition/supplyside-stories-episode-28-sustainability-commitments-tsi-group-bio-active">TSI Bio-Active Ingredients leads the way (naturalproductsinsider.com)</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/">Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Perfect Capsules, Every Time</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 16:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A manufacturer recently asked us why they suddenly could only fill their glucosamine capsules to 80% of their weight from previous production runs when the only change was the production lot from the raw material supplier. With the material being in spec they wanted to know: what is the significance of bulk density, tap density, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/">Perfect Capsules, Every Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A manufacturer recently asked us why they suddenly could only fill their glucosamine capsules to 80% of their weight from previous production runs when the only change was the production lot from the raw material supplier. With the material being in spec they wanted to know: what is the significance of bulk density, tap density, and particle size when encapsulating?</p>
<p>All supplement capsule manufacturers face the same challenges of sourcing raw materials that flow freely while also having the proper density to fit the required dosage into the capsule. Tap density is a good indicator of how a product will respond to the encapsulation process but is not commonly specified by raw material producers. Bulk density however is usually included on a material spec and therefore is used to determine the suitability for encapsulation. Generally speaking, the bulk density and tap density are proportional, and so this works as an adequate indicator on how a product will perform in capsule making – until it doesn’t.</p>
<p>For one thing particle size matters – a larger particle size will generally increase tap density – but so do both particle size <em>distribution</em> and particle <em>shape</em> as well. And these can all vary significantly while the material is still within spec.</p>
<p>The solution? Choose a manufacturer and supplier with decades of experience producing the product from raw material to finished dose and who understands the unique challenges of each dosage form. In this case TSI Group offers a capsule grade glucosamine specifically processed to ensure consistent filling from lot to lot, every time.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/">Perfect Capsules, Every Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cracking the Code for the Ideal Glucosamine Tablet</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GRIP]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 21:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The most successful companies in the supplement industry spend their resources focused obsessively on how to anticipate and meet consumer demands for products that deliver the ingredients they want, in a form that is convenient and easy to take. While these trends have resulted in the growth of soft chews, RTD’s, soft gels, and gummies, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/">Cracking the Code for the Ideal Glucosamine Tablet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The most successful companies in the supplement industry spend their resources focused obsessively on how to anticipate and meet consumer demands for products that deliver the ingredients they want, in a form that is convenient and easy to take. While these trends have resulted in the growth of soft chews, RTD’s, soft gels, and gummies, the most popular dosage form for glucosamine remains tablets. Tablets allow versatility in combining several active ingredients and can be made to dissolve at a specific rate to allow for maximum efficacy.</p>
<p>As tablet makers strive to separate themselves from the competition, they reach a point where they believe they’ve done all they can to maximize every aspect of their production. So it is with glucosamine, where most suppliers use a spec like particle size distribution and companies assume this is the most effective means of measuring how easily a powder can be compressed into a tablet. They believe that once they have done all they can within these industry standards that there is no more benefit to be gained here. We believe there is much more to be gained by using a granule that is truly compressible, and that can provide tangible gains in tablet size and complexity.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nutraingredients-usa.com/News/Promotional-Features/Cracking-the-Code-to-Create-Ideal-Glucosamine-Tablets">Cracking the Code to Create Ideal Glucosamine Tablets (nutraingredients-usa.com)</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/">Cracking the Code for the Ideal Glucosamine Tablet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When it Comes to Tablets, Size Matters</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/when-it-comes-to-tablets-size-matters/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/when-it-comes-to-tablets-size-matters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GRIP]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 06:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://glucosaminepro.wpengine.com/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US FDA has for several years published recommended guidelines for maximum tablet size for makers of dietary supplements. Though non-binding in nature, these guidelines were developed through extensive research on tablet size and shape, and the ages of individuals taking the supplements. Perhaps not all that surprising is that older adults were more sensitive [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/when-it-comes-to-tablets-size-matters/">When it Comes to Tablets, Size Matters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US FDA has for several years published recommended guidelines for maximum tablet size for makers of dietary supplements. Though non-binding in nature, these guidelines were developed through extensive research on tablet size and shape, and the ages of individuals taking the supplements. Perhaps not all that surprising is that older adults were more sensitive to tablet size than others<sup>1</sup>. Since glucosamine is typically taken for joint pain and to address the effects of osteoarthritis this is especially relevant to our customers. Keeping to, or exceeding these guidelines offers a competitive advantage for any supplement manufacturer. Companies not only have to make sure their products contain enough active ingredients to deliver the desired dosages, they also have to meet the demand for more diverse and complex matrices in order to keep up with consumer trends.</p>
<p>TSI Group is focused on helping these companies achieve this competitive advantage. We’ve cracked the code on ideal glucosamine granule which can reduce tablet sizes by up to 20% based on the reduced need for binders and excipients. This can be done without compromising tablet hardness and ultimately tablet quality. Full FDA guideline can be found here.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/87344/download">Size, Shape, and Other Physical Attributes of Generic Tablets and Capsules Guidance for Industry (fda.gov)</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Pill-Tablets-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Pill-Tablets-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Pill-Tablets.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><sup>1 </sup>Geller AI, Shehab N, Weidle NJ, Lovegrove MC, Wolpert BJ, Timbo BB, et al. Emergency Department Visits for Adverse Events Related to Dietary Supplements. N Engl J Med 2015;373(16):1531–40.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/when-it-comes-to-tablets-size-matters/">When it Comes to Tablets, Size Matters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/when-it-comes-to-tablets-size-matters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
