<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The Glucosamine Experts™</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:52:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-Favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</title>
		<link>/next-generation-glucosamine/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/</link>
					<comments>/next-generation-glucosamine/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 18:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine is the most common nutritional supplement taken for joint health and it is widely used around the world. A study by Li et al.【1】recently looked at the health tracking from 2006 to 2010 of nearly 500,000 people aged 40-70 in the UK. According to the data, 19.1% of the subjects in the study reported [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/">Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine is the most common nutritional supplement taken for joint health and it is widely used around the world. A study by <em>Li </em><em>et al.<sup>【1</sup><sup>】</sup></em>recently looked at the health tracking from 2006 to 2010 of nearly 500,000 people aged 40-70 in the UK. According to the data, 19.1% of the subjects in the study reported regularly taking glucosamine. The results of the study were then corrected for 27 potential contributing factors. These included the understanding that glucosamine users generally have healthier than average lifestyles. With this data the study developed an accurate data model and reported the relationship between regular glucosamine use and reduced mortality.</p>
<h4>What did the study find?</h4>
<p>The study found that regular glucosamine use was significantly associated with a 15% lower risk of mortality from all causes. More specifically it was tied to an 18% reduction in cardiovascular disease mortality, 6% for cancer mortality, 27% for respiratory mortality and 26% for digestive mortality. These findings were reported independent of other potential factors including demographics, lifestyle behaviors, health status, drug use and other supplement use. The results reported by the authors are consistent with other prior epidemiological studies looking at glucosamine and mortality.<sup>【2-4</sup><sup>】</sup>Inspired by this study, <em>Hideya Shintani et al<sup>【</sup><sup>5</sup><sup>】</sup></em>in 2021 suggested that further research should focus on the efficacy of glucosamine in anti-aging.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1902" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-300x177.jpg" alt="" width="433" height="255" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-300x177.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-1024x605.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-768x454.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1.jpg 1276w" sizes="(max-width: 433px) 100vw, 433px" /></p>
<h4><strong>References</strong></h4>
<ol>
<li>Li Z-H, Gao X, Chung VC, et Associations of regular glucosamine use with all-cause and cause-specific mortality: a large prospective cohort study. Ann Rheum Dis 2020;79:829–36. <a href="https://ard.bmj.com/content/79/6/829">doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-217176</a></li>
<li>Bell GA, Kantor ED, Lampe JW, et Use of glucosamine and chondroitin in relation to mortality. Eur J Epidemiol 2012;27:593–603. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10654-012-9714-6">doi:10.1007/s10654-012-9714-6</a></li>
<li>Brasky TM, Lampe JW, Slatore CG, et al. Use of glucosamine and chondroitin and lung cancer risk in the vitamins and lifestyle (vital) cohort. Cancer Causes Control 2011;22:1333–42. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10552-011-9806-8">doi:10.1007/s10552-011-9806-8</a></li>
<li>Ma H, Li X, Sun D, et Association of habitual glucosamine use with risk of cardiovascular disease: prospective study in UK Biobank. BMJ 2019;365:l1628. <a href="https://www.bmj.com/content/365/bmj.l1628">doi:10.1136/bmj.l1628</a></li>
<li>Hideya Shintani, Hisashi Ashida, Tomoya Shintani,Shifting the focus of d-glucosamine from a dietary supplement for knee osteoarthritis to a potential anti-aging drug,Human Nutrition &amp; Metabolism,Volume 26,2021,200134,ISSN 2666-1497. <a href="http://doi.org/10.1016/j.hnm.2021.200134"><u>doi.org/10.1016/j.hnm.2021.200134</u></a></li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/">Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/next-generation-glucosamine/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</title>
		<link>/optimized-ingredients/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/</link>
					<comments>/optimized-ingredients/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Optimized Ingredients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We at TSI Group, the exclusive manufacturers of GlucosaGreen® vegetal glucosamine are curious about something. We know glucosamine has been around for generations. It is a common supplement taken to relieve joint pain in humans. It can also help companion animals remain active and healthy. But that’s not the curious part. What is GlucosaGreen®? GlucosaGreen® [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimized-ingredients/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/">How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We at TSI Group, the exclusive manufacturers of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> vegetal glucosamine are curious about something. We know glucosamine has been around for generations. It is a common supplement taken to relieve joint pain in humans. It can also help companion animals remain active and healthy. But that’s not the curious part.</p>
<h4><strong>What is GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup>?</strong></h4>
<p>GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the same ingredient with the same bio-activity as traditional glucosamine. It is just made in a different way. Instead of harvesting the building blocks for the supplement from shellfish, we produce it by processing glucose from non-GMO corn. Same glucosamine, different process to make it. Again, nothing curious about that.</p>
<p>GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is glucosamine; the magic is in how making it impacts the environment. The process to make GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> reduces waste generation by 98% and reduces the carbon footprint by 80% over shellfish derived glucosamine. But once more, this is not what we are curious about.</p>
<h4><strong>So why are you curious?</strong></h4>
<p>We are curious because we can’t understand why anyone looking to relieve joint pain with glucosamine would ever reach for a product that is made from shellfish. We thought that maybe consumers just don’t know that it is the same supplement. So we checked a number of Google search terms to see what comes up and the one we were most intrigued by was:</p>
<p>“How to get glucosamine naturally”</p>
<p>This is a frequently asked question on Google, and there&#8217;s a good chance this is because people don&#8217;t want to take the supplement knowing that it comes from shellfish. Curiously, almost every link we found from this search contained virtually the same statement: <em>glucosamine occurs naturally in shellfish, otherwise it is made synthetically</em>. Unfortunately this is simply not true. GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is derived naturally from non-GMO corn via fermentation. That’s it. No shellfish, no extreme waste, no synthesis. But the same glucosamine as always.</p>
<p>So look for the logo and insist on GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> for you and your pet and take care of your health, your pet’s health, and the health of the planet. GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the Next Generation Glucosamine<sup>TM</sup>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimized-ingredients/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/">How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/optimized-ingredients/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>GlucosaGreen® Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</title>
		<link>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/</link>
					<comments>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 23:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/">GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular" >
				
				
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
								<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner">We refer to our GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> Next Generation Glucosamine as being “environmentally friendly” or “sustainably produced.” But what does that mean really? These terms have no standards or regulations to define them. Just like “natural” or “organic” these words can lose their meaning and become just marketing terms. So we wonder: does putting “green” at the beginning or end of a name really mean anything?
<h4><strong>How is glucosamine made?</strong></h4>
For generations glucosamine has been the world’s most widely used dietary supplement for joint pain. Historically most glucosamine in the world has been made by extracting a substance called chitin from shellfish shells. Chitin is processed into the glucosamine powder that makes its way into tablets, capsules, and other finished doses. TSI Group, who remains the largest glucosamine producer in the world, was one of the first to offer a product that is not derived from shellfish. Instead GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is derived from non-GMO corn through a unique fermentation process. The output, however is the same exact glucosamine that is made from shellfish.
<h4><strong>Why Glucosa<em>Green<sup>®</sup></em>?</strong></h4>
GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> instantly made glucosamine available to people with shellfish allergies and kosher diets, but its impact is far bigger. Producing GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is much gentler on the environment than producing glucosamine from shellfish. We can measure this impact in a couple of ways – either by the amount of waste it generates or by the carbon footprint of the processes. Making glucosamine from shellfish generates 455 times the finished product’s weight in wastewater and produces 5 ½ times its weight in solid waste. Making GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> reduces the wastewater flow by over 99% and the solid waste volume by over 98%.
<h4><strong>Why should I care?</strong></h4>
Wastewater and solid waste are usually local issues but carbon footprint measures the global impact. Certain gasses that accumulate in our atmosphere can cause gradual warming of the planet through the greenhouse effect. This will eventually cause a rise in sea levels, an increase in extreme weather, and other changes to the natural balance of our environment. Limiting these changes will help future generations who will all compete for limited resources. The <a href="https://www.eia.gov/energyexplained/energy-and-the-environment/greenhouse-gases.php">US Energy Information Administration</a> identifies several greenhouse gasses, including carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>), methane (CH<sub>4</sub>), nitrous oxide (N<sub>2</sub>O), and fluorocarbons. These emissions can be measured as carbon dioxide equivalents so we can compare greenhouse gasses relative to carbon. In 2019, the world’s total carbon emission was 33.6 billion tons, or 4.4 tons per capita. About 26% of the total carbon emissions came from food production, including supplements.

More specifically the carbon footprint from farming and fishing of crustaceans is 7.9 kg per kg of shellfish. By contrast the planting and harvesting of corn has a net carbon footprint of 0.25 kg per kg of corn. Electric and heat energy and the purification of wastewater are the main contributors to these emissions.
<h4><strong>Bottom Line</strong></h4>
How do these numbers add up? Harvesting and processing the shellfish needed to make 1 MT of glucosamine creates a total emission of 71 MT of CO<sub>2</sub>. That same ton of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> releases only 14.5 MT of CO<sub>2</sub>. That’s over <em>one million metric tons of CO<sub>2</sub></em> saved to meet the world’s demand for glucosamine! And now you know why GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the Next Generation Glucosamine. It’s the same supplement trusted for people and their pets for years, but much gentler on the planet. It is exclusively from TSI Group, the world’s largest glucosamine manufacturer and The Glucosamine Experts<sup>TM</sup>.</div>
			</div>
			</div>			
				
				
				
				
			</div>		
				
				
			</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/">GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</title>
		<link>/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/</link>
					<comments>/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 17:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#glucosamine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#healthandwellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine has been used for years to relieve joint pain due to osteoarthritis. Clinical studies have shown that it can help reduce cartilage degradation as well as aid in the rebuilding of cartilage. It has provided much needed relief from pain for millions of people and animals and enabled them to live more active, healthy [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/">The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine has been used for years to relieve joint pain due to osteoarthritis. Clinical studies have shown that it can help reduce cartilage degradation as well as aid in the rebuilding of cartilage. It has provided much needed relief from pain for millions of people and animals and enabled them to live more active, healthy lives. Well The Glucosamine Experts are not stopping there. And the industry headlines this week are talking about our latest accomplishment: demonstrating GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup>’s potential for gut health and muscle health.</p>
<h3>What makes you such an expert?</h3>
<p>We at TSI Group take our tag line “The Glucosamine Experts” seriously. That means not just knowing the history of the product, but looking to the future and understanding what else this supplement can do. This promising research shows the potential for GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> to be an even bigger “anti-aging” supplement than previously thought. Add this news to the other unique features of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> and it&#8217;s pretty clear we&#8217;ve earned the title:</p>
<ul>
<li>producing GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> from non-GMO corn instead of shellfish reduces water use and waste generation by over 96%</li>
<li>TSI Group is the world&#8217;s largest glucosamine manufacturer</li>
<li>we have unparalleled expertise in creating raw material forms perfectly suited to specific finished dose production</li>
</ul>
<p>Past, present, and future – GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> exclusively from The Glucosamine Experts at TSI Group Ltd just can’t be beat.</p>
<p><em>Nutrition Insight,</em> 10-12-21, Latest News: “<a href="https://www.nutritioninsight.com/news/tsis-vegetarian-GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;-has-gut-health-and-anti-aging-benefits-study-finds.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TSI’s vegetarian GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> has gut health and anti-aging benefits, study finds</a>”.</p>
<p><em>Nutritional Outlook, </em>10-15-21, Featured Content: “<a href="https://www.nutritionaloutlook.com/view/new-research-demonstrates-potential-gut-health-benefits-of-glucosamine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New research demonstrates potential gut health benefits of glucosamine</a>”.</p>
<p><em>Nutraceutical Business Review,</em> 10-12-21, Breaking &amp; Research News: “<a href="https://nutraceuticalbusinessreview.com/news/article_page/Human_trial_demonstrates_TSI_ingredients_gut_health_benefits/179860" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Human trial demonstrates TSI ingredient’s gut health benefits</a>”.</p>
<p><em>NutraI</em><em>ngredients-USA, </em>10-12-21, E-news Special Edition: Looking ahead to SupplySide West 2021: “<a href="https://www.nutraingredients-usa.com/Article/2021/10/12/Supplier-taps-gut-health-benefits-of-glucosamine/?utm_source=Newsletter_SponsoredSpecial&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Newsletter%2BSponsoredSpecial&amp;c=jrwH8OrK1rSXFnePFvnlo2tfZHyKwBRH&amp;cid=DM982921&amp;bid=1735151110" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Supplier taps gut health benefits of glucosamine</a>.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/">The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</title>
		<link>/science-and-research/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/</link>
					<comments>/science-and-research/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 22:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science and Research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Matt and Pete talk about how TSI Group came to be the experts in glucosamine and the value that will deliver for our customers. TSI Bio-Active Ingredients leads the way (naturalproductsinsider.com)</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/">Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Matt an<a href="https://www.naturalproductsinsider.com/sports-nutrition/supplyside-stories-episode-28-sustainability-commitments-tsi-group-bio-active"><img class="wp-image-997 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories-300x276.png" alt="" width="187" height="171" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories-300x276.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories.png 624w" sizes="(max-width: 187px) 100vw, 187px" /></a>d Pete talk about how TSI Group came to be the experts in glucosamine and the value that will deliver for our customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.naturalproductsinsider.com/sports-nutrition/supplyside-stories-episode-28-sustainability-commitments-tsi-group-bio-active">TSI Bio-Active Ingredients leads the way (naturalproductsinsider.com)</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/">Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/science-and-research/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All Glucosamine is Not the Same</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 22:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Too often in the world of supplements we think of certain ingredients as commodities. For these items there are so many options available in the supply chain that determining the best choice often feels like a decision that can only be driven by price. Glucosamine is one of those ingredients. It is widely used to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/">All Glucosamine is Not the Same</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Too often in the world of supplements we think of certain ingredients as commodities. For these items there are so many options available in the supply chain that determining the best choice often feels like a decision that can only be driven by price. Glucosamine is one of those ingredients. It is widely used to promote joint health, and many human and pet supplement brands have at least one glucosamine SKU. For buyers, finding glucosamine is easy since most distributors handle it, and most will look to get the order based on their ability to meet or beat competitive prices. And these distributors and their customers will agree that glucosamine is a difficult powder to compress. Consequently no matter where it is sourced or how it is processed, turning it into tablets will be a challenge.</p>
<p>Here’s the problem with that kind of thinking in business. Once we say “all (fill in the blank) is the same” we accept the commonly known limitations and then we miss the breakthroughs that could allow us to separate from our competition.</p>
<p>In that spirit we say: don’t miss this breakthrough. TSI has poured decades of experience into developing granules for glucosamine and we have cracked the code to the ideal tablet grade granule. In fact it is truly such a breakthrough that we’ve given the process a name: <em>OptiTab</em> Technology.</p>
<h4>How much do we believe in <em>OptiTab </em>Technology?</h4>
<p>We invite any maker of glucosamine tablets to challenge us to make their exact same product, only better. Measurably better. Better quality, fewer defects, higher yields, and smaller size. It is all possible, and at a cost that ultimately allows our customers to put more profit into their bottom line while <em>making a better product!</em></p>
<p>In the next few weeks we will be officially releasing the TSI Challenge. Take us up on it and put our knowledge to work for you. Then watch as we continue to solve problems you did not even know you had.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/">All Glucosamine is Not the Same</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Resetting the Meaning of Branded Ingredients</title>
		<link>/optimized-ingredients/resetting-the-meaning-of-branded-ingredients/</link>
					<comments>/optimized-ingredients/resetting-the-meaning-of-branded-ingredients/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 01:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Optimized Ingredients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#brandedingredients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#glucosamine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#smallertablets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a society that loves to use buzzwords, terms can become so overused they lose their meaning. But key words like “transparency,” “sustainability” and “quality” should be more than their meanings – they are the pillars of trust that drive the engine of product development and consumer loyalty. Manufacturers often turn to branded ingredients to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimized-ingredients/resetting-the-meaning-of-branded-ingredients/">Resetting the Meaning of Branded Ingredients</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a society that loves to use buzzwords, terms can become so overused they lose their meaning. But key words like “transparency,” “sustainability” and “quality” should be more than their meanings – they are the pillars of trust that drive the engine of product development and consumer loyalty. Manufacturers often turn to branded ingredients to demonstrate these qualities to consumers in the hopes of building trust and loyalty.</p>
<p>In the supply side however, it’s no longer enough to just provide branded ingredients. While the term “brand” has cache and imparts the concept of something special or extra, it does not necessarily mean consistency or transparency, just as “natural” does not always automatically mean sustainable. Words and the values they convey matter to consumers who rely on CPG companies to have their backs when it comes to safety and consistency.</p>
<p>According to a 2019 survey by Trust Transparency Center, consumers are not gullible and will do their research: they want access to reliable knowledge they can trust to choose products and brands that align with their values. Glucosamine, one of the world’s most popular and well-known supplements, is a keen example:</p>
<ul>
<li>49% of people who regularly use glucosamine are influenced by sustainability concerns<sup>1</sup></li>
<li>83% of Millennials say it’s important to buy from companies whose values align with theirs <sup>2</sup></li>
<li>40% of people who take glucosamine don&#8217;t know how it is sourced and/or processed <sup>1</sup></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Transparency</strong></h2>
<p>Studies show that consumers who take supplements want to know where the ingredients come from. Those same studies however show a gap between their desire and their actual understanding of what this process involves. The industry treats many supplement ingredients as commodities and the supply chain is usually a web of traders, brokers, exporters, importers and distributors. Each step adds complexity and makes the origins harder to trace. Regulations require traceability in the form of documents, but these are not readily available to consumers, making this trail difficult to follow.</p>
<p>The idea of traceability is further compromised when supplement makers use branded ingredients to give the illusion of transparency. Many brands are simply just created for marketing purposes, and the actual ingredients are made by unknown third parties who are often selected strictly on price.</p>
<p>TSI Group has always made transparency a core principle. Our leading branded ingredient – <a href="https://www.glucosagreen.com/">GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup></a> &#8211; is manufactured, imported, and distributed by TSI. There are no third-party manufacturers, traders or brokers. The product is made in the same factory to the same exacting standards lot after lot.</p>
<p>Further, our website <a href="https://www.glucosagreen.com/">glucosagreen.com</a> is published specifically for consumers, giving them direct access to the actual ingredient manufacturer. This is the only way to give them the assurance of consistent quality and the confidence that they are truly buying a product that is aligned with their values.</p>
<h2><strong>Sustainability</strong></h2>
<p>When it comes to sustainability, consumers clearly want to buy products that come from companies who share their values. For example, more than 60% of people worldwide who regularly use glucosamine are willing to pay a price premium for an environmentally friendly and sustainably sourced product.<sup>4</sup></p>
<p><a href="https://www.glucosagreen.com/">GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup></a> is sustainable as it is not dependent on the supply of crustacean shells but instead from non-GMO corn. Additionally <a href="https://www.glucosagreen.com/">GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup></a> produces only 2% of the waste compared to shellfish glucosamine and reduces waste water discharge by an incredible 99.6%. TSI is continuing to work to eliminate all waste water discharge from our <a href="https://www.glucosagreen.com/">GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup></a> production.</p>
<p>This is also great news for pet supplement brands &#8211; 84% of dog owners surveyed would pay more for pet supplements that have ingredients that are made through a “green” process. <sup>3</sup></p>
<h2><strong>Quality</strong></h2>
<p>When it comes to how the raw materials come together to make a finished product, consistency is the key. Whether that is in tablet size, quality, taste, color, dosage, or any other criteria, brands that meet customer expectations every time will thrive.</p>
<p>Getting there is not so easy however when supply chains are as complex as they are with supplement ingredients. Finished-dose producers often need to process raw materials once they are received from the manufacturer, since keeping a consistent source is often a challenge. This is especially true when making tablets or capsules. The properties of one source may differ from another, even when both meet a certain given spec. This creates the need for additional processing that adds costs in handling, additional raw materials, lower yields, and testing. That is in addition to limiting flexibility out of concern for tablet and capsule size. Eliminating most, if not all of these costs simply adds to the bottom line, and producing smaller tablets is certainly a competitive advantage.</p>
<p>Watch this space at <a href="/">glucosamineexperts.com</a> for upcoming news on TSI’s exclusive OptiTab process for simply the best granule available for tableting, and more announcements offering special formulations for capsules and soft chews.</p>
<p>The next generation of wellness supplements isn’t in the future – it’s here now. Ensure your supplier is more than a supplier, but a partner in the formulating and production of dietary supplements that fulfill consumers’ need for quality, traceability, and sustainability. <a href="https://www.tsigroupltd.com/bio-active-ingredients-division">TSI Group</a> may very well be that partner.</p>
<p><sup>1 </sup>Trust Transparency Center. (2019). <em>2019 2<sup>nd</sup> annual Trust Transparency Center Single Ingredient Trade Association Consumer Survey</em></p>
<p><sup>2</sup>Consumer Culture [5W PR 2020 Report]</p>
<p><sup>3 </sup>Survey conducted by TSI Group November 2020, pet owners in the US</p>
<p><sup>4 </sup>Trust Transparency Center. (2020). ITC Insights: Consumer Survey Glucosamine Focus</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimized-ingredients/resetting-the-meaning-of-branded-ingredients/">Resetting the Meaning of Branded Ingredients</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/optimized-ingredients/resetting-the-meaning-of-branded-ingredients/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Perfect Capsules, Every Time</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 16:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A manufacturer recently asked us why they suddenly could only fill their glucosamine capsules to 80% of their weight from previous production runs when the only change was the production lot from the raw material supplier. With the material being in spec they wanted to know: what is the significance of bulk density, tap density, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/">Perfect Capsules, Every Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A manufacturer recently asked us why they suddenly could only fill their glucosamine capsules to 80% of their weight from previous production runs when the only change was the production lot from the raw material supplier. With the material being in spec they wanted to know: what is the significance of bulk density, tap density, and particle size when encapsulating?</p>
<p>All supplement capsule manufacturers face the same challenges of sourcing raw materials that flow freely while also having the proper density to fit the required dosage into the capsule. Tap density is a good indicator of how a product will respond to the encapsulation process but is not commonly specified by raw material producers. Bulk density however is usually included on a material spec and therefore is used to determine the suitability for encapsulation. Generally speaking, the bulk density and tap density are proportional, and so this works as an adequate indicator on how a product will perform in capsule making – until it doesn’t.</p>
<p>For one thing particle size matters – a larger particle size will generally increase tap density – but so do both particle size <em>distribution</em> and particle <em>shape</em> as well. And these can all vary significantly while the material is still within spec.</p>
<p>The solution? Choose a manufacturer and supplier with decades of experience producing the product from raw material to finished dose and who understands the unique challenges of each dosage form. In this case TSI Group offers a capsule grade glucosamine specifically processed to ensure consistent filling from lot to lot, every time.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/">Perfect Capsules, Every Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/capsule-grade-glucosamine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Glucosamine Benefits Beyond Joint Pain</title>
		<link>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/</link>
					<comments>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 15:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine with chondroitin is a widely used combination supplement used by many individuals who suffer from osteoarthritis and joint pain. Both glucosamine and chondroitin are natural compounds found in cartilage and are readily available as dietary supplements. A recent US study, however indicates that there may be more benefits beyond those for joint health. The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/">Glucosamine Benefits Beyond Joint Pain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine with chondroitin is a widely used combination supplement used by many individuals who suffer from osteoarthritis and joint pain. Both glucosamine and chondroitin are natural compounds found in cartilage and are readily available as dietary supplements.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.vitafoodsinsights.com/speciality/glucosamine-chondroitin-may-reduce-overall-mortality" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent US study</a>, however indicates that there may be more benefits beyond those for joint health. The study, published by the Journal of the American Board of Family Medicine (JABFM), sought to investigate the association of daily use of glucosamine/chondroitin with cardiovascular and overall mortality. Results of this indicated that regular supplementation with glucosamine and chondroitin was associated with a significant reduction in all-cause mortality and cardiovascular related deaths.</p>
<p>Citation: The Journal of the American Board of Family Medicine November 2020, 33 (6) 842-847.</p>
<p>Read the full results here: <em>J Am Board Fam Med</em>. DOI: <a href="https://www.jabfm.org/content/33/6/842" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10.3122/jabfm.2020.06.200110</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/">Glucosamine Benefits Beyond Joint Pain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cracking the Code for the Ideal Glucosamine Tablet</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GRIP]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 21:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The most successful companies in the supplement industry spend their resources focused obsessively on how to anticipate and meet consumer demands for products that deliver the ingredients they want, in a form that is convenient and easy to take. While these trends have resulted in the growth of soft chews, RTD’s, soft gels, and gummies, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/">Cracking the Code for the Ideal Glucosamine Tablet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The most successful companies in the supplement industry spend their resources focused obsessively on how to anticipate and meet consumer demands for products that deliver the ingredients they want, in a form that is convenient and easy to take. While these trends have resulted in the growth of soft chews, RTD’s, soft gels, and gummies, the most popular dosage form for glucosamine remains tablets. Tablets allow versatility in combining several active ingredients and can be made to dissolve at a specific rate to allow for maximum efficacy.</p>
<p>As tablet makers strive to separate themselves from the competition, they reach a point where they believe they’ve done all they can to maximize every aspect of their production. So it is with glucosamine, where most suppliers use a spec like particle size distribution and companies assume this is the most effective means of measuring how easily a powder can be compressed into a tablet. They believe that once they have done all they can within these industry standards that there is no more benefit to be gained here. We believe there is much more to be gained by using a granule that is truly compressible, and that can provide tangible gains in tablet size and complexity.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nutraingredients-usa.com/News/Promotional-Features/Cracking-the-Code-to-Create-Ideal-Glucosamine-Tablets">Cracking the Code to Create Ideal Glucosamine Tablets (nutraingredients-usa.com)</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/">Cracking the Code for the Ideal Glucosamine Tablet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/cracking-the-code-for-the-ideal-glucosamine-tablet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
