<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>pmazzilli_admin_22, Author at The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/pmazzilli_admin_22/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/author/pmazzilli_admin_22/</link>
	<description>The Glucosamine Experts™</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 21:11:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-Favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>pmazzilli_admin_22, Author at The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<link>/author/pmazzilli_admin_22/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Efficacy study of glucosamine hydrochloride in bone and joint health</title>
		<link>/library/efficacy-study-of-glucosamine-hydrochloride-in-bone-and-joint-health/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 20:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Which is better, glucosamine hydrochloride or glucosamine sulfate complex salt? In terms of free-base glucosamine (C6H13NO5) content, Glucosamine Hydrochloride (83.1%) has higher content than Glucosamine Sulfate Sodium Chloride (62.5%) and Glucosamine Sulfate Potassium Chloride (59.2%). Many studies have shown that the only biologically active substance among various glucosamine compounds is free-base glucosamine. (Block JA. et [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/library/efficacy-study-of-glucosamine-hydrochloride-in-bone-and-joint-health/">Efficacy study of glucosamine hydrochloride in bone and joint health</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Which is better, glucosamine hydrochloride or glucosamine sulfate complex salt?</p>



<p>In terms of free-base glucosamine (C6H13NO5) content, Glucosamine Hydrochloride (83.1%) has higher content than Glucosamine Sulfate Sodium Chloride (62.5%) and Glucosamine Sulfate Potassium Chloride (59.2%). Many studies have shown that the only biologically active substance among various glucosamine compounds is free-base glucosamine. (Block JA. et al., 2010)</p>



<p>Glucosamine sulfate has more clinical effectiveness studies than Glucosamine Hydrochloride. However. in 2006, the European Medicines Agency (EMA) published an Assessment Report on Glucomed625 mg glucosamine hydrochloride , which concluded that there was a favorable risk/benefit ratio for the glucosamine hydrochloride product, on the basis of submitted literature on glucosamine sulfate, as the formulations are not considered to be different in terms of safety or efficacy. Therefore, it can be considered that a precedent was set whereby clinical data for glucosamine sulfate are also applicable to the evaluation of glucosamine hydrochloride. (Bertin P. et al., 2014)</p>



<p>At present, more and more countries in the EU have updated the active ingredient of the marketed glucosamine sulfate &amp; glucosamine hydrochloride medicines to more scientific free-base glucosamine.</p>



<div id="download-link"></div>
<script
type="text/javascript"
src="https://unpkg.com/@ungap/url-search-params@0.2.2/min.js"
></script>

<script>
const file = '/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Efficacy-Study-TSI.pdf';
linkDiv = document.getElementById("download-link");

if (file) {
    linkDiv.innerHTML = `<div style="padding:1em 0;">
    <a href="${file}" class="ge-bold" target="_blank"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ge-download-icon ge-download-allowed" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2">
    <path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M12 10v6m0 0l-3-3m3 3l3-3m2 8H7a2 2 0 01-2-2V5a2 2 0 012-2h5.586a1 1 0 01.707.293l5.414 5.414a1 1 0 01.293.707V19a2 2 0 01-2 2z" />
    </svg></a">
    <p><a href="${file}" class="ge-bold uppercase ge-text-gray" target="_blank">Please click here to open/download the file.</a></p>
    </div>`;
} else {
    linkDiv.innerHTML = `<div style="padding:1em 0;">
    <h2>Seems like something is not right</h2>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="ge-download-icon cursor-not-allowed ge-download-not-allowed" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2">
    <path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M10 14l2-2m0 0l2-2m-2 2l-2-2m2 2l2 2m7-2a9 9 0 11-18 0 9 9 0 0118 0z" />
    </svg>
    <p class="uppercase">Please contact us, we will send you the file you requested.</p>
    </div>`;
}
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/library/efficacy-study-of-glucosamine-hydrochloride-in-bone-and-joint-health/">Efficacy study of glucosamine hydrochloride in bone and joint health</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Comprehensive Guide to Global Clinical Research of Glucosamine</title>
		<link>/library/comprehensive-guide-to-global-clinical-research-of-glucosamine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 18:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine is a high valued, naturally occurring amino sugar, categorized as a nonvitamin and nonmineral dietarysupplement, with demonstrated efficacy for arthritis, neurological disorders, and inflammatory health ailments. Becauseof its diverse industrial applications in food, pharma, and cosmetics, the market demand is expected to exceed 40,000metric tons in 2022. Fill the form to download the file.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/library/comprehensive-guide-to-global-clinical-research-of-glucosamine/">Comprehensive Guide to Global Clinical Research of Glucosamine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-3 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-column">
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Glucosamine is a high valued, naturally occurring amino sugar, categorized as a nonvitamin and nonmineral dietary<br>supplement, with demonstrated efficacy for arthritis, neurological disorders, and inflammatory health ailments. Because<br>of its diverse industrial applications in food, pharma, and cosmetics, the market demand is expected to exceed 40,000<br>metric tons in 2022.</p>



<p>Fill the form to download the file.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-column">
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2.js"></script>
<script>
  hbspt.forms.create({
css:"",
    region: "na1",
    portalId: "7930619",
    formId: "f19cbd35-0a76-40d1-a07d-60ce1cc1d97a",
   redirectUrl:"/thank-you-for-downloading?file=https%3A%2F%2Fuzunu-cdn-assets.s3.us-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fglucosamine-experts%2Fknowledge-center-documents%2FResearchBreakdownonGlucosamine-June22.pdf",
   locale: 'en',
      translations: {
        en: {
          submitText: "Download File",
          }}
    });
</script>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/library/comprehensive-guide-to-global-clinical-research-of-glucosamine/">Comprehensive Guide to Global Clinical Research of Glucosamine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Complete Guide to the History and Applications of the Supplement Glucosamine</title>
		<link>/library/complete-guide-to-the-history-and-applications-of-the-supplement-glucosamine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 17:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine sulfate tends to rebuild the damaged cartilage, thus restoring articular function in most chronic arthrosic patients. The long-term combined structure-modifying and symptom-modifying effects of glucosamine sulphate suggest that it could be a disease modifying agent in osteoarthritis</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/library/complete-guide-to-the-history-and-applications-of-the-supplement-glucosamine/">Complete Guide to the History and Applications of the Supplement Glucosamine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-6 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-4 wp-block-column">
<p>Glucosamine sulfate tends to rebuild the damaged cartilage, thus restoring articular function in most chronic arthrosic patients.</p>



<p>The long-term combined structure-modifying and symptom-modifying effects of glucosamine sulphate suggest that it could be a disease modifying agent in osteoarthritis</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-5 wp-block-column">
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2.js"></script>
<script>
  hbspt.forms.create({
    region: "na1",
    portalId: "7930619",
    formId: "f19cbd35-0a76-40d1-a07d-60ce1cc1d97a",
   redirectUrl:"/thank-you-for-downloading?file=https%3A%2F%2Fuzunu-cdn-assets.s3.us-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fglucosamine-experts%2Fknowledge-center-documents%2FGlucosamine%2BResearch%2BJune%2B2022.pdf",
   locale: 'en',
      translations: {
        en: {
          submitText: "Download File",
          }}
    });
</script>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/library/complete-guide-to-the-history-and-applications-of-the-supplement-glucosamine/">Complete Guide to the History and Applications of the Supplement Glucosamine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arthritis in Dogs</title>
		<link>/pet-health/arthritis-in-dogs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 19:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pet Health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s well known that dogs help us to keep healthier and happier in life. They get us outdoors and keep us active, and just like us, they need to look after their joints to keep them in the best possible shape. Good joint health improves quality of life for all of us, so we need [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/pet-health/arthritis-in-dogs/">Arthritis in Dogs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It&#8217;s well known that dogs help us to keep healthier and happier in life. They get us outdoors and keep us active, and just like us, they need to look after their joints to keep them in the best possible shape. Good joint health improves quality of life for all of us, so we need to look after our pets as well as ourselves.</p>



<p>Below are a number of &nbsp;common indicators of arthritis:</p>



<ul><li>Difficulty getting up or down</li><li>they develop a limp or favour one leg over the other</li><li>reluctance to go up or down stairs</li><li>stiff swollen or sore joints</li><li>changes in the way they sit</li><li>licking their joints</li><li>Lethargic or trying to avoid physical activity</li></ul>



<p>Arthritis in dogs is a common condition especially as they age. Here are some tips to help combat arthritis for our pets.</p>



<p><strong>Keep them at a healthy weight </strong>&#8211; arthritis puts extra strain on joints so keeping your dog at a healthy weight will make a significant difference to their comfort and activity levels.</p>



<p><strong>Give them regular exercise </strong>&#8211; moderate exercise helps to keep dogs’ joints healthy, however overdoing it can lead to issues for our pets. You may need to avoid activities that put too much strain on joints such as jumping. Ensuring that your dog gets the right amount of exercise will keep them lean and support the muscles surrounding their joints.</p>



<p><strong>Add supplements to their diet</strong> &#8211; there are number of supplements available that can help to ease arthritis pain in dogs. This can help to keep their joints healthy and inhibit inflammation. Speak to your vet about which ones might be right for your pet.</p>



<p><strong>Keep their bedding clean and comfortable</strong> &#8211; sore joints can make sleeping painful so make sure their bedding is clean and soft. In some cases, orthopaedic beds may be a good choice.</p>



<p>Joint pain is a common condition affecting dogs of all ages and breeds. It affects the quality of life and can potentially lead to serious conditions and injuries if not treated. Following these tips will help your dog to stay healthy and active for longer, in turn keeping you healthy and active as well.</p>



<p><em>Article reposted with permission from</em>&nbsp;<a href="https://wdggcdn.wildcat-digital.com/2022/07/16/arthritis-in-dogs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup></a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/pet-health/arthritis-in-dogs/">Arthritis in Dogs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</title>
		<link>/science-and-research/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/</link>
					<comments>/science-and-research/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 18:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science and Research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine is the most common nutritional supplement taken for joint health and it is widely used around the world. A study by Li et al.【1】recently looked at the health tracking from 2006 to 2010 of nearly 500,000 people aged 40-70 in the UK. According to the data, 19.1% of the subjects in the study reported [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/">Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine is the most common nutritional supplement taken for joint health and it is widely used around the world. A study by <em>Li </em><em>et al.<sup>【1</sup><sup>】</sup></em>recently looked at the health tracking from 2006 to 2010 of nearly 500,000 people aged 40-70 in the UK. According to the data, 19.1% of the subjects in the study reported regularly taking glucosamine. The results of the study were then corrected for 27 potential contributing factors. These included the understanding that glucosamine users generally have healthier than average lifestyles. With this data the study developed an accurate data model and reported the relationship between regular glucosamine use and reduced mortality.</p>
<h4>What did the study find?</h4>
<p>The study found that regular glucosamine use was significantly associated with a 15% lower risk of mortality from all causes. More specifically it was tied to an 18% reduction in cardiovascular disease mortality, 6% for cancer mortality, 27% for respiratory mortality and 26% for digestive mortality. These findings were reported independent of other potential factors including demographics, lifestyle behaviors, health status, drug use and other supplement use. The results reported by the authors are consistent with other prior epidemiological studies looking at glucosamine and mortality.<sup>【2-4</sup><sup>】</sup>Inspired by this study, <em>Hideya Shintani et al<sup>【</sup><sup>5</sup><sup>】</sup></em>in 2021 suggested that further research should focus on the efficacy of glucosamine in anti-aging.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1902" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-300x177.jpg" alt="" width="433" height="255" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-300x177.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-1024x605.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-768x454.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1.jpg 1276w" sizes="(max-width: 433px) 100vw, 433px" /></p>
<h4><strong>References</strong></h4>
<ol>
<li>Li Z-H, Gao X, Chung VC, et Associations of regular glucosamine use with all-cause and cause-specific mortality: a large prospective cohort study. Ann Rheum Dis 2020;79:829–36. <a href="https://ard.bmj.com/content/79/6/829">doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-217176</a></li>
<li>Bell GA, Kantor ED, Lampe JW, et Use of glucosamine and chondroitin in relation to mortality. Eur J Epidemiol 2012;27:593–603. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10654-012-9714-6">doi:10.1007/s10654-012-9714-6</a></li>
<li>Brasky TM, Lampe JW, Slatore CG, et al. Use of glucosamine and chondroitin and lung cancer risk in the vitamins and lifestyle (vital) cohort. Cancer Causes Control 2011;22:1333–42. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10552-011-9806-8">doi:10.1007/s10552-011-9806-8</a></li>
<li>Ma H, Li X, Sun D, et Association of habitual glucosamine use with risk of cardiovascular disease: prospective study in UK Biobank. BMJ 2019;365:l1628. <a href="https://www.bmj.com/content/365/bmj.l1628">doi:10.1136/bmj.l1628</a></li>
<li>Hideya Shintani, Hisashi Ashida, Tomoya Shintani,Shifting the focus of d-glucosamine from a dietary supplement for knee osteoarthritis to a potential anti-aging drug,Human Nutrition &amp; Metabolism,Volume 26,2021,200134,ISSN 2666-1497. <a href="http://doi.org/10.1016/j.hnm.2021.200134"><u>doi.org/10.1016/j.hnm.2021.200134</u></a></li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/">Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/science-and-research/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We at TSI Group, the exclusive manufacturers of GlucosaGreen® vegetal glucosamine are curious about something. We know glucosamine has been around for generations. It is a common supplement taken to relieve joint pain in humans. It can also help companion animals remain active and healthy. But that’s not the curious part. What is GlucosaGreen®? GlucosaGreen® [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/">How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We at TSI Group, the exclusive manufacturers of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> vegetal glucosamine are curious about something. We know glucosamine has been around for generations. It is a common supplement taken to relieve joint pain in humans. It can also help companion animals remain active and healthy. But that’s not the curious part.</p>
<h4><strong>What is GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup>?</strong></h4>
<p>GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the same ingredient with the same bio-activity as traditional glucosamine. It is just made in a different way. Instead of harvesting the building blocks for the supplement from shellfish, we produce it by processing glucose from non-GMO corn. Same glucosamine, different process to make it. Again, nothing curious about that.</p>
<p>GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is glucosamine; the magic is in how making it impacts the environment. The process to make GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> reduces waste generation by 98% and reduces the carbon footprint by 80% over shellfish derived glucosamine. But once more, this is not what we are curious about.</p>
<h4><strong>So why are you curious?</strong></h4>
<p>We are curious because we can’t understand why anyone looking to relieve joint pain with glucosamine would ever reach for a product that is made from shellfish. We thought that maybe consumers just don’t know that it is the same supplement. So we checked a number of Google search terms to see what comes up and the one we were most intrigued by was:</p>
<p>“How to get glucosamine naturally”</p>
<p>This is a frequently asked question on Google, and there&#8217;s a good chance this is because people don&#8217;t want to take the supplement knowing that it comes from shellfish. Curiously, almost every link we found from this search contained virtually the same statement: <em>glucosamine occurs naturally in shellfish, otherwise it is made synthetically</em>. Unfortunately this is simply not true. GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is derived naturally from non-GMO corn via fermentation. That’s it. No shellfish, no extreme waste, no synthesis. But the same glucosamine as always.</p>
<p>So look for the logo and insist on GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> for you and your pet and take care of your health, your pet’s health, and the health of the planet. GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the Next Generation Glucosamine<sup>TM</sup>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/">How to Get Glucosamine Naturally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/how-to-get-glucosamine-naturally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>GlucosaGreen® Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</title>
		<link>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/</link>
					<comments>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 23:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/">GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular" >
				
				
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
								<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner">We refer to our GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> Next Generation Glucosamine as being “environmentally friendly” or “sustainably produced.” But what does that mean really? These terms have no standards or regulations to define them. Just like “natural” or “organic” these words can lose their meaning and become just marketing terms. So we wonder: does putting “green” at the beginning or end of a name really mean anything?
<h4><strong>How is glucosamine made?</strong></h4>
For generations glucosamine has been the world’s most widely used dietary supplement for joint pain. Historically most glucosamine in the world has been made by extracting a substance called chitin from shellfish shells. Chitin is processed into the glucosamine powder that makes its way into tablets, capsules, and other finished doses. TSI Group, who remains the largest glucosamine producer in the world, was one of the first to offer a product that is not derived from shellfish. Instead GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is derived from non-GMO corn through a unique fermentation process. The output, however is the same exact glucosamine that is made from shellfish.
<h4><strong>Why Glucosa<em>Green<sup>®</sup></em>?</strong></h4>
GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> instantly made glucosamine available to people with shellfish allergies and kosher diets, but its impact is far bigger. Producing GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is much gentler on the environment than producing glucosamine from shellfish. We can measure this impact in a couple of ways – either by the amount of waste it generates or by the carbon footprint of the processes. Making glucosamine from shellfish generates 455 times the finished product’s weight in wastewater and produces 5 ½ times its weight in solid waste. Making GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> reduces the wastewater flow by over 99% and the solid waste volume by over 98%.
<h4><strong>Why should I care?</strong></h4>
Wastewater and solid waste are usually local issues but carbon footprint measures the global impact. Certain gasses that accumulate in our atmosphere can cause gradual warming of the planet through the greenhouse effect. This will eventually cause a rise in sea levels, an increase in extreme weather, and other changes to the natural balance of our environment. Limiting these changes will help future generations who will all compete for limited resources. The <a href="https://www.eia.gov/energyexplained/energy-and-the-environment/greenhouse-gases.php">US Energy Information Administration</a> identifies several greenhouse gasses, including carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>), methane (CH<sub>4</sub>), nitrous oxide (N<sub>2</sub>O), and fluorocarbons. These emissions can be measured as carbon dioxide equivalents so we can compare greenhouse gasses relative to carbon. In 2019, the world’s total carbon emission was 33.6 billion tons, or 4.4 tons per capita. About 26% of the total carbon emissions came from food production, including supplements.

More specifically the carbon footprint from farming and fishing of crustaceans is 7.9 kg per kg of shellfish. By contrast the planting and harvesting of corn has a net carbon footprint of 0.25 kg per kg of corn. Electric and heat energy and the purification of wastewater are the main contributors to these emissions.
<h4><strong>Bottom Line</strong></h4>
How do these numbers add up? Harvesting and processing the shellfish needed to make 1 MT of glucosamine creates a total emission of 71 MT of CO<sub>2</sub>. That same ton of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> releases only 14.5 MT of CO<sub>2</sub>. That’s over <em>one million metric tons of CO<sub>2</sub></em> saved to meet the world’s demand for glucosamine! And now you know why GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the Next Generation Glucosamine. It’s the same supplement trusted for people and their pets for years, but much gentler on the planet. It is exclusively from TSI Group, the world’s largest glucosamine manufacturer and The Glucosamine Experts<sup>TM</sup>.</div>
			</div>
			</div>			
				
				
				
				
			</div>		
				
				
			</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/">GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/next-generation-glucosamine/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</title>
		<link>/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/</link>
					<comments>/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 17:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science and Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#glucosamine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#healthandwellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine has been used for years to relieve joint pain due to osteoarthritis. Clinical studies have shown that it can help reduce cartilage degradation as well as aid in the rebuilding of cartilage. It has provided much needed relief from pain for millions of people and animals and enabled them to live more active, healthy [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/">The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine has been used for years to relieve joint pain due to osteoarthritis. Clinical studies have shown that it can help reduce cartilage degradation as well as aid in the rebuilding of cartilage. It has provided much needed relief from pain for millions of people and animals and enabled them to live more active, healthy lives. Well The Glucosamine Experts are not stopping there. And the industry headlines this week are talking about our latest accomplishment: demonstrating GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup>’s potential for gut health and muscle health.</p>
<h3>What makes you such an expert?</h3>
<p>We at TSI Group take our tag line “The Glucosamine Experts” seriously. That means not just knowing the history of the product, but looking to the future and understanding what else this supplement can do. This promising research shows the potential for GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> to be an even bigger “anti-aging” supplement than previously thought. Add this news to the other unique features of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> and it&#8217;s pretty clear we&#8217;ve earned the title:</p>
<ul>
<li>producing GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> from non-GMO corn instead of shellfish reduces water use and waste generation by over 96%</li>
<li>TSI Group is the world&#8217;s largest glucosamine manufacturer</li>
<li>we have unparalleled expertise in creating raw material forms perfectly suited to specific finished dose production</li>
</ul>
<p>Past, present, and future – GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> exclusively from The Glucosamine Experts at TSI Group Ltd just can’t be beat.</p>
<p><em>Nutrition Insight,</em> 10-12-21, Latest News: “<a href="https://www.nutritioninsight.com/news/tsis-vegetarian-GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;-has-gut-health-and-anti-aging-benefits-study-finds.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TSI’s vegetarian GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> has gut health and anti-aging benefits, study finds</a>”.</p>
<p><em>Nutritional Outlook, </em>10-15-21, Featured Content: “<a href="https://www.nutritionaloutlook.com/view/new-research-demonstrates-potential-gut-health-benefits-of-glucosamine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New research demonstrates potential gut health benefits of glucosamine</a>”.</p>
<p><em>Nutraceutical Business Review,</em> 10-12-21, Breaking &amp; Research News: “<a href="https://nutraceuticalbusinessreview.com/news/article_page/Human_trial_demonstrates_TSI_ingredients_gut_health_benefits/179860" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Human trial demonstrates TSI ingredient’s gut health benefits</a>”.</p>
<p><em>NutraI</em><em>ngredients-USA, </em>10-12-21, E-news Special Edition: Looking ahead to SupplySide West 2021: “<a href="https://www.nutraingredients-usa.com/Article/2021/10/12/Supplier-taps-gut-health-benefits-of-glucosamine/?utm_source=Newsletter_SponsoredSpecial&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Newsletter%2BSponsoredSpecial&amp;c=jrwH8OrK1rSXFnePFvnlo2tfZHyKwBRH&amp;cid=DM982921&amp;bid=1735151110" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Supplier taps gut health benefits of glucosamine</a>.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/">The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/science-and-research/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</title>
		<link>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/</link>
					<comments>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 22:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Process Improvement for Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Matt and Pete talk about how TSI Group came to be the experts in glucosamine and the value that will deliver for our customers. TSI Bio-Active Ingredients leads the way (naturalproductsinsider.com)</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/">Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Matt an<a href="https://www.naturalproductsinsider.com/sports-nutrition/supplyside-stories-episode-28-sustainability-commitments-tsi-group-bio-active"><img class="wp-image-997 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories-300x276.png" alt="" width="187" height="171" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories-300x276.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Supplyside-stories.png 624w" sizes="(max-width: 187px) 100vw, 187px" /></a>d Pete talk about how TSI Group came to be the experts in glucosamine and the value that will deliver for our customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.naturalproductsinsider.com/sports-nutrition/supplyside-stories-episode-28-sustainability-commitments-tsi-group-bio-active">TSI Bio-Active Ingredients leads the way (naturalproductsinsider.com)</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/">Bio-Active Ingredients&#8217; Marketing Team Discusses the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/process-improvement-for-glucosamine/bio-active-ingredients-marketing-team-discusses-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All Glucosamine is Not the Same</title>
		<link>/next-generation-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/</link>
					<comments>/next-generation-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 22:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Too often in the world of supplements we think of certain ingredients as commodities. For these items there are so many options available in the supply chain that determining the best choice often feels like a decision that can only be driven by price. Glucosamine is one of those ingredients. It is widely used to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/">All Glucosamine is Not the Same</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Too often in the world of supplements we think of certain ingredients as commodities. For these items there are so many options available in the supply chain that determining the best choice often feels like a decision that can only be driven by price. Glucosamine is one of those ingredients. It is widely used to promote joint health, and many human and pet supplement brands have at least one glucosamine SKU. For buyers, finding glucosamine is easy since most distributors handle it, and most will look to get the order based on their ability to meet or beat competitive prices. And these distributors and their customers will agree that glucosamine is a difficult powder to compress. Consequently no matter where it is sourced or how it is processed, turning it into tablets will be a challenge.</p>
<p>Here’s the problem with that kind of thinking in business. Once we say “all (fill in the blank) is the same” we accept the commonly known limitations and then we miss the breakthroughs that could allow us to separate from our competition.</p>
<p>In that spirit we say: don’t miss this breakthrough. TSI has poured decades of experience into developing granules for glucosamine and we have cracked the code to the ideal tablet grade granule. In fact it is truly such a breakthrough that we’ve given the process a name: <em>OptiTab</em> Technology.</p>
<h4>How much do we believe in <em>OptiTab </em>Technology?</h4>
<p>We invite any maker of glucosamine tablets to challenge us to make their exact same product, only better. Measurably better. Better quality, fewer defects, higher yields, and smaller size. It is all possible, and at a cost that ultimately allows our customers to put more profit into their bottom line while <em>making a better product!</em></p>
<p>In the next few weeks we will be officially releasing the TSI Challenge. Take us up on it and put our knowledge to work for you. Then watch as we continue to solve problems you did not even know you had.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/next-generation-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/">All Glucosamine is Not the Same</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/next-generation-glucosamine/all-glucosamine-is-not-the-same/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
