<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Next Generation Glucosamine Archives - The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/beyond-joint-health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/beyond-joint-health/</link>
	<description>The Glucosamine Experts™</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:52:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-Favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Next Generation Glucosamine Archives - The Glucosamine Experts™</title>
	<link>/category/beyond-joint-health/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</title>
		<link>/beyond-joint-health/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/</link>
					<comments>/beyond-joint-health/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 18:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine is the most common nutritional supplement taken for joint health and it is widely used around the world. A study by Li et al.【1】recently looked at the health tracking from 2006 to 2010 of nearly 500,000 people aged 40-70 in the UK. According to the data, 19.1% of the subjects in the study reported [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/beyond-joint-health/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/">Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine is the most common nutritional supplement taken for joint health and it is widely used around the world. A study by <em>Li </em><em>et al.<sup>【1</sup><sup>】</sup></em>recently looked at the health tracking from 2006 to 2010 of nearly 500,000 people aged 40-70 in the UK. According to the data, 19.1% of the subjects in the study reported regularly taking glucosamine. The results of the study were then corrected for 27 potential contributing factors. These included the understanding that glucosamine users generally have healthier than average lifestyles. With this data the study developed an accurate data model and reported the relationship between regular glucosamine use and reduced mortality.</p>
<h4>What did the study find?</h4>
<p>The study found that regular glucosamine use was significantly associated with a 15% lower risk of mortality from all causes. More specifically it was tied to an 18% reduction in cardiovascular disease mortality, 6% for cancer mortality, 27% for respiratory mortality and 26% for digestive mortality. These findings were reported independent of other potential factors including demographics, lifestyle behaviors, health status, drug use and other supplement use. The results reported by the authors are consistent with other prior epidemiological studies looking at glucosamine and mortality.<sup>【2-4</sup><sup>】</sup>Inspired by this study, <em>Hideya Shintani et al<sup>【</sup><sup>5</sup><sup>】</sup></em>in 2021 suggested that further research should focus on the efficacy of glucosamine in anti-aging.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1902" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-300x177.jpg" alt="" width="433" height="255" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-300x177.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-1024x605.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1-768x454.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Glucosamine-and-Mortalitiy-3-22-graph_Page_1.1.jpg 1276w" sizes="(max-width: 433px) 100vw, 433px" /></p>
<h4><strong>References</strong></h4>
<ol>
<li>Li Z-H, Gao X, Chung VC, et Associations of regular glucosamine use with all-cause and cause-specific mortality: a large prospective cohort study. Ann Rheum Dis 2020;79:829–36. <a href="https://ard.bmj.com/content/79/6/829">doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-217176</a></li>
<li>Bell GA, Kantor ED, Lampe JW, et Use of glucosamine and chondroitin in relation to mortality. Eur J Epidemiol 2012;27:593–603. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10654-012-9714-6">doi:10.1007/s10654-012-9714-6</a></li>
<li>Brasky TM, Lampe JW, Slatore CG, et al. Use of glucosamine and chondroitin and lung cancer risk in the vitamins and lifestyle (vital) cohort. Cancer Causes Control 2011;22:1333–42. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10552-011-9806-8">doi:10.1007/s10552-011-9806-8</a></li>
<li>Ma H, Li X, Sun D, et Association of habitual glucosamine use with risk of cardiovascular disease: prospective study in UK Biobank. BMJ 2019;365:l1628. <a href="https://www.bmj.com/content/365/bmj.l1628">doi:10.1136/bmj.l1628</a></li>
<li>Hideya Shintani, Hisashi Ashida, Tomoya Shintani,Shifting the focus of d-glucosamine from a dietary supplement for knee osteoarthritis to a potential anti-aging drug,Human Nutrition &amp; Metabolism,Volume 26,2021,200134,ISSN 2666-1497. <a href="http://doi.org/10.1016/j.hnm.2021.200134"><u>doi.org/10.1016/j.hnm.2021.200134</u></a></li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/beyond-joint-health/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/">Can Regular Glucosamine Use Lower Mortality?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/beyond-joint-health/can-regular-glucosamine-use-lower-mortality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>GlucosaGreen® Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</title>
		<link>/beyond-joint-health/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/</link>
					<comments>/beyond-joint-health/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 23:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/beyond-joint-health/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/">GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular" >
				
				
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
								<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner">We refer to our GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> Next Generation Glucosamine as being “environmentally friendly” or “sustainably produced.” But what does that mean really? These terms have no standards or regulations to define them. Just like “natural” or “organic” these words can lose their meaning and become just marketing terms. So we wonder: does putting “green” at the beginning or end of a name really mean anything?
<h4><strong>How is glucosamine made?</strong></h4>
For generations glucosamine has been the world’s most widely used dietary supplement for joint pain. Historically most glucosamine in the world has been made by extracting a substance called chitin from shellfish shells. Chitin is processed into the glucosamine powder that makes its way into tablets, capsules, and other finished doses. TSI Group, who remains the largest glucosamine producer in the world, was one of the first to offer a product that is not derived from shellfish. Instead GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is derived from non-GMO corn through a unique fermentation process. The output, however is the same exact glucosamine that is made from shellfish.
<h4><strong>Why Glucosa<em>Green<sup>®</sup></em>?</strong></h4>
GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> instantly made glucosamine available to people with shellfish allergies and kosher diets, but its impact is far bigger. Producing GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is much gentler on the environment than producing glucosamine from shellfish. We can measure this impact in a couple of ways – either by the amount of waste it generates or by the carbon footprint of the processes. Making glucosamine from shellfish generates 455 times the finished product’s weight in wastewater and produces 5 ½ times its weight in solid waste. Making GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> reduces the wastewater flow by over 99% and the solid waste volume by over 98%.
<h4><strong>Why should I care?</strong></h4>
Wastewater and solid waste are usually local issues but carbon footprint measures the global impact. Certain gasses that accumulate in our atmosphere can cause gradual warming of the planet through the greenhouse effect. This will eventually cause a rise in sea levels, an increase in extreme weather, and other changes to the natural balance of our environment. Limiting these changes will help future generations who will all compete for limited resources. The <a href="https://www.eia.gov/energyexplained/energy-and-the-environment/greenhouse-gases.php">US Energy Information Administration</a> identifies several greenhouse gasses, including carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>), methane (CH<sub>4</sub>), nitrous oxide (N<sub>2</sub>O), and fluorocarbons. These emissions can be measured as carbon dioxide equivalents so we can compare greenhouse gasses relative to carbon. In 2019, the world’s total carbon emission was 33.6 billion tons, or 4.4 tons per capita. About 26% of the total carbon emissions came from food production, including supplements.

More specifically the carbon footprint from farming and fishing of crustaceans is 7.9 kg per kg of shellfish. By contrast the planting and harvesting of corn has a net carbon footprint of 0.25 kg per kg of corn. Electric and heat energy and the purification of wastewater are the main contributors to these emissions.
<h4><strong>Bottom Line</strong></h4>
How do these numbers add up? Harvesting and processing the shellfish needed to make 1 MT of glucosamine creates a total emission of 71 MT of CO<sub>2</sub>. That same ton of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> releases only 14.5 MT of CO<sub>2</sub>. That’s over <em>one million metric tons of CO<sub>2</sub></em> saved to meet the world’s demand for glucosamine! And now you know why GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> is the Next Generation Glucosamine. It’s the same supplement trusted for people and their pets for years, but much gentler on the planet. It is exclusively from TSI Group, the world’s largest glucosamine manufacturer and The Glucosamine Experts<sup>TM</sup>.</div>
			</div>
			</div>			
				
				
				
				
			</div>		
				
				
			</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/beyond-joint-health/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/">GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Contributes to Global Carbon Neutrality</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/beyond-joint-health/glucosagreen-contributes-to-global-carbon-neutrality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</title>
		<link>/glucosamine-experts/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/</link>
					<comments>/glucosamine-experts/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 17:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#glucosamine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#healthandwellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine has been used for years to relieve joint pain due to osteoarthritis. Clinical studies have shown that it can help reduce cartilage degradation as well as aid in the rebuilding of cartilage. It has provided much needed relief from pain for millions of people and animals and enabled them to live more active, healthy [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/glucosamine-experts/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/">The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine has been used for years to relieve joint pain due to osteoarthritis. Clinical studies have shown that it can help reduce cartilage degradation as well as aid in the rebuilding of cartilage. It has provided much needed relief from pain for millions of people and animals and enabled them to live more active, healthy lives. Well The Glucosamine Experts are not stopping there. And the industry headlines this week are talking about our latest accomplishment: demonstrating GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup>’s potential for gut health and muscle health.</p>
<h3>What makes you such an expert?</h3>
<p>We at TSI Group take our tag line “The Glucosamine Experts” seriously. That means not just knowing the history of the product, but looking to the future and understanding what else this supplement can do. This promising research shows the potential for GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> to be an even bigger “anti-aging” supplement than previously thought. Add this news to the other unique features of GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> and it&#8217;s pretty clear we&#8217;ve earned the title:</p>
<ul>
<li>producing GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> from non-GMO corn instead of shellfish reduces water use and waste generation by over 96%</li>
<li>TSI Group is the world&#8217;s largest glucosamine manufacturer</li>
<li>we have unparalleled expertise in creating raw material forms perfectly suited to specific finished dose production</li>
</ul>
<p>Past, present, and future – GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> exclusively from The Glucosamine Experts at TSI Group Ltd just can’t be beat.</p>
<p><em>Nutrition Insight,</em> 10-12-21, Latest News: “<a href="https://www.nutritioninsight.com/news/tsis-vegetarian-GlucosaGreen&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;-has-gut-health-and-anti-aging-benefits-study-finds.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TSI’s vegetarian GlucosaGreen<sup>®</sup> has gut health and anti-aging benefits, study finds</a>”.</p>
<p><em>Nutritional Outlook, </em>10-15-21, Featured Content: “<a href="https://www.nutritionaloutlook.com/view/new-research-demonstrates-potential-gut-health-benefits-of-glucosamine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New research demonstrates potential gut health benefits of glucosamine</a>”.</p>
<p><em>Nutraceutical Business Review,</em> 10-12-21, Breaking &amp; Research News: “<a href="https://nutraceuticalbusinessreview.com/news/article_page/Human_trial_demonstrates_TSI_ingredients_gut_health_benefits/179860" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Human trial demonstrates TSI ingredient’s gut health benefits</a>”.</p>
<p><em>NutraI</em><em>ngredients-USA, </em>10-12-21, E-news Special Edition: Looking ahead to SupplySide West 2021: “<a href="https://www.nutraingredients-usa.com/Article/2021/10/12/Supplier-taps-gut-health-benefits-of-glucosamine/?utm_source=Newsletter_SponsoredSpecial&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Newsletter%2BSponsoredSpecial&amp;c=jrwH8OrK1rSXFnePFvnlo2tfZHyKwBRH&amp;cid=DM982921&amp;bid=1735151110" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Supplier taps gut health benefits of glucosamine</a>.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/glucosamine-experts/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/">The Glucosamine Experts are Making Headlines!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/glucosamine-experts/the-glucosamine-experts-are-making-headlines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Glucosamine Benefits Beyond Joint Pain</title>
		<link>/beyond-joint-health/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/</link>
					<comments>/beyond-joint-health/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pmazzilli_admin_22]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 15:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Next Generation Glucosamine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine with chondroitin is a widely used combination supplement used by many individuals who suffer from osteoarthritis and joint pain. Both glucosamine and chondroitin are natural compounds found in cartilage and are readily available as dietary supplements. A recent US study, however indicates that there may be more benefits beyond those for joint health. The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/beyond-joint-health/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/">Glucosamine Benefits Beyond Joint Pain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glucosamine with chondroitin is a widely used combination supplement used by many individuals who suffer from osteoarthritis and joint pain. Both glucosamine and chondroitin are natural compounds found in cartilage and are readily available as dietary supplements.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.vitafoodsinsights.com/speciality/glucosamine-chondroitin-may-reduce-overall-mortality" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent US study</a>, however indicates that there may be more benefits beyond those for joint health. The study, published by the Journal of the American Board of Family Medicine (JABFM), sought to investigate the association of daily use of glucosamine/chondroitin with cardiovascular and overall mortality. Results of this indicated that regular supplementation with glucosamine and chondroitin was associated with a significant reduction in all-cause mortality and cardiovascular related deaths.</p>
<p>Citation: The Journal of the American Board of Family Medicine November 2020, 33 (6) 842-847.</p>
<p>Read the full results here: <em>J Am Board Fam Med</em>. DOI: <a href="https://www.jabfm.org/content/33/6/842" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10.3122/jabfm.2020.06.200110</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/beyond-joint-health/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/">Glucosamine Benefits Beyond Joint Pain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Glucosamine Experts™</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/beyond-joint-health/glucosamine-benefits-beyond-joint-pain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
